(The Shadow Sovereign)
(Episode 17)
- Why are you here to attend to me?   - Father.
What did you make me drink?
It's...
It's medicine, Father.
You're ill. It's medicine.
Did the Crown Prince send you here?
No... It's not.
No...
The Crown Prince was exactly the one who told me to come.
Father.
Outside the hall...
No.
The whole palace
is full of Cui Jin Zhi's troops.
Did you know?
You brought
all of this on yourself.
You brought this on yourself!
What
wonderful children
I have raised.
Father.
It's not like that.
His Majesty suddenly collapsed.
There may be traitors plotting in secret.
Starting today, the palace gates will be tightly guarded.
Crown Prince Li Chong will temporarily rule the nation.
No outsiders are allowed inside.
(Did you know?)
(You brought)
(all of this on yourself.)
(You brought this on yourself!)
What wonderful children
I have raised.
(Father.)
(I never wanted any of this.)
(But I'm clearly the rightful princess with the highest status.)
(I should be the one you cherish most.)
(But you...)
(You only care about that wretched Zhao Yang.)
(It's all your fault!)
(You're the one to blame!)
The Crown Prince is about to take the throne.
You'll just have to stay here for now, Your Highness.
Once things settle down,
I'll find somewhere for you to go.
Eat something first.
You're not going to eat?
Trying to starve yourself to prove a point?
Or are you waiting for someone?
If you want to talk about Shen Xiao,
just say it.
You really do care about him.
Fine.
I'll tell you.
Shen Xiao is dead.
I killed him.
Show me proof that he's dead.
I won't believe in your empty talks.
Didn't you stir up the Crown Prince's fears with empty talks, too?
Zhao Yang.
I know you better than anyone else.
The Crown Prince will never forgive what you've done.
From now on,
if you just do as I say,
I'll make sure you're safe.
You helped the Crown Prince plot treason.
You'll never die in peace.
Shen Xiao is loyal to the throne and the nation.
He won't die so easily.
He's the one who won't die in peace.
A nobody from a poor family like him wants to control the court,
covet the princess, and rival the noble clans.
Someone that arrogant deserves to die.
You probably don't know yet.
He came back to the capital with evidence against the Crown Prince.
I killed him by the Yellow River with a single strike.
You actually killed Shen Xiao?
I did
kill Shen Xiao.
But you can't blame me for it.
What do you mean?
You helped him rise
and gave him power.
Putting him right in the middle of the storm
and making him the Crown Prince's biggest threat.
Wasn't that all you?
It was you
who destroyed him step by step.
Father.
A Top Scholar steps into the Emperor's hall for the first time.
Sending him to Lingnan feels like he's being treated unfairly.
Why don't you
make him an eighth-rank Supervising Censor
and let him stay in the capital?
There's people you can use, Li Yan.
Why make things harder for yourself?
Do you mean
Shen Xiao?
Do you think Shen Xiao dares steal grain from Wannian County?
Transport the grain.
Your Highness, the Ministry of Revenue brought soldiers,
stormed the manor and grabbed the grain
with the Emperor's grain requisition decree.
I'm the one who took the grain!
I request to investigate this ownerless grain
and give the people a proper explanation.
You're asking for trouble.
From now on,
I'm all you've got.
Get out.
You'll come around.
I'll wait for you.
When you finally come around,
come find me.
Where's Cui Jin Zhi?
If Your Highness has something to say,
I can deliver the message.
Tell him that I've come around.
Please help me give something to Cui Jin Zhi.
Eunuch.
Your Highness.
You are finally here, Your Highness.
Your Highness is His Majesty's only hope now.
The palace is under tight security now.
You must be careful, Your Highness.
Don't worry, Eunuch.
Cold Palace. That's the only way out now.
Over there! Go check over there!
Take my token and go after her.
Yes!
Wait! Don't hurt her.
She's over there!
- Hurry!   - Stop right there!
- There!   - Stop!
Hurry!
Don't let her get away!
- After her!   - Yes!
Stop!
She's over there!
You're still alive.
You survived.
That's great.
I'm back.
I still have the military token.
Why are the Shence Camp soldiers here?
We had to improvise in an emergency.
On my way back to the capital,
I saw Cui Jin Zhi leading his private troops into the Imperial City.
I had to detour and find General Yuan.
I urged him to enter the capital and protect His Majesty.
If we waited for the token, it would've been too late.
Regardless,
I've made you suffer.
Since I ascended the throne,
I've worked tirelessly day and night.
But now, I'm gravely ill and can't recover.
I'm afraid I've failed my ancestors' trust.
Crown Prince Li Chong's virtue shines bright.
His rule brings peace and wisdom.
Everyone in court and the realm looks up to him.
That brings me comfort.
- I hereby pass the throne to...   - You traitorous son!
Arrest the traitors! Nobody move!
Who's there? Who?
Who's there? Let go of me!
Zheng Shu.
You betrayed me.
Li Chong.
This ridiculous farce
needs to end now.
Cui Jin Zhi commands 30,000 elite troops.
He has already taken control of the palace.
Father, you are old and senile.
You should retire and enjoy your remaining years.
I,
Li Chong,
am the rightful new ruler of Ye by Heaven's will!
Where's Cui Jin Zhi?
Where is Cui Jin Zhi?
Protect me, the emperor!
Come and protect me!
Cui Jin Zhi, all your men are dead.
Just surrender.
Dream on.
Protect the general!
Cui Jin Zhi, surrender now.
No way.
Wipe out the remaining enemies.
Guard His Majesty!
Zheng Shu, I've treated you well.
You wicked woman!
I've kept my promise to you.
The Zheng clan has nothing to do with this rebellion.
His Majesty has already made his decision.
I know what you're up to.
I can help you.
Sister-in-law, what are you getting at?
I didn't hear a thing today.
Even if you get the Shence Camp transfer order,
it'll still be tough for the army to enter the city.
The Nine Gates are guarded by families loyal to the Eastern Palace.
But the Western Gate is guarded by my clan, the Zheng clan.
This is my clan's token.
(Zheng)
Zhao Yang, I'm not begging you.
I'm giving you a win-win option.
You can get rid of your biggest enemy.
As for me,
I'm fighting for
my family's future and mine.
Crown Prince Li Chong,
you seized land and grain and raised your own private army.
Now, you plot to seize the throne and poison His Majesty.
Do you admit your guilt?
Me? Admit my guilt?
I am the crown prince.
It's my right
to take the throne.
Someone as twisted as you
think you are worthy to rule this nation?
Me?
Unworthy?
I am unworthy?
What about him? Is he any more worthy?
You're obsessed with alchemy
and drained the nation's strength.
You play power games to control the court.
You stir up factional strife.
You make me, the Crown Prince, live on edge every day!
You.
You distrust every one of your sons.
You give us titles, but you never stop watching your back.
If I didn't fight for power or raise my own troops,
I might be the one who dies tomorrow!
Rather than watch
this great nation fall apart in your hands,
I'd rather...
I'd rather drag you down with me straight to hell!
Crown Prince.
Our score
is settled.
(Prison of the Ministry of Justice)
You came.
Since you wanted to see me,
I'll see you off myself.
His Majesty showed mercy.
I've already heard the decree to exile me to Lingnan.
It's a long journey.
The snow makes it hard to travel.
So, I won't go.
Sure.
All these years,
I've let you down.
On our wedding day, I shouldn't have...
It's all in the past.
That's right.
It's all over now.
When we were kids,
you bandaged my wounds
and said
a ruler should win people over with virtue.
- That's not right.   - How is it not right?
A ruler should lead with virtue
and win people over with kindness.
You might be the Crown Prince's study companion,
but you are still your own self.
Back then I thought
that little girl saw things clearer than anyone.
But how
did everything change later?
People change.
Everyone changes.
It was my mistake.
I let you down.
I, Cui Jin Zhi,
was born into a wealthy family
and raised among the powerful.
Now, I've lost.
It's fate and destiny.
I accept it.
But to lose to someone like Shen Xiao, a man from a humble family.
I can't accept that.
You're still the same, after all.
Que Nu!
If there's a next life,
don't be a princess.
I won't be a member of the Cui family either.
Will you...
(Prison of the Ministry of Justice)
Oh no! Prisoner Cui Jin Zhi has committed suicide!
(Que Nu.)
(I brought your favorite pastries.)